<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<Organism_Record>
  <Organism_ID>ASD10900000_1</Organism_ID>
  <Organism>Pseudomonas aeruginosa</Organism>
  <Organism_Latin>Pseudomonas aeruginosa</Organism_Latin>
  <UniProt_ID>Q9HUL8</UniProt_ID>
  <Seq_Length>633</Seq_Length>
  <Molecule_Weight>69748</Molecule_Weight>
  <KEGG_ID>pae:PA4946</KEGG_ID>
  <Orthology_ID>K03572</Orthology_ID>
  <Function_Summary>This protein is involved in the repair of mismatches in DNA. It is required for dam-dependent methyl-directed DNA mismatch repair. May act as a molecular matchmaker, a protein that promotes the formation of a stable complex between two or more DNA-binding proteins in an ATP-dependent manner without itself being part of a final effector complex (By similarity).</Function_Summary>
  <Pfam_ID>PF01119:DNA_mis_repair@@PF02518:HATPase_c@@PF08676:MutL_C</Pfam_ID>
  <Allosteric_Activator_Count>0</Allosteric_Activator_Count>
  <Allosteric_Inhibitor_Count>0</Allosteric_Inhibitor_Count>
  <Allosteric_Regulator_Count>0</Allosteric_Regulator_Count>
  <Function_List>
    <Funtion>
      <Detail>Interacting selectively and non-covalently with double-stranded DNA containing one or more mismatches.</Detail>
      <Keyword>Mismatched DNA binding</Keyword>
      <Ontology_ID>GO:0030983</Ontology_ID>
    </Funtion>
    <Funtion>
      <Detail>Interacting selectively and non-covalently with ATP, adenosine 5'-triphosphate, a universally important coenzyme and enzyme regulator.</Detail>
      <Keyword>ATP binding</Keyword>
      <Ontology_ID>GO:0005524</Ontology_ID>
    </Funtion>
  </Function_List>
  <BioProcess_List>
    <BioProcess>
      <Detail>Any cellular metabolic process involving deoxyribonucleic acid. This is one of the two main types of nucleic acid, consisting of a long, unbranched macromolecule formed from one, or more commonly, two, strands of linked deoxyribonucleotides.</Detail>
      <Keyword>DNA metabolic process</Keyword>
      <Ontology_ID>GO:0006259</Ontology_ID>
    </BioProcess>
    <BioProcess>
      <Detail>The process of restoring DNA after damage. Genomes are subject to damage by chemical and physical agents in the environment (e.g. UV and ionizing radiations, chemical mutagens, fungal and bacterial toxins, etc.) and by free radicals or alkylating agents endogenously generated in metabolism. DNA is also damaged because of errors during its replication. A variety of different DNA repair pathways have been reported that include direct reversal, base excision repair, nucleotide excision repair, photoreactivation, bypass, double-strand break repair pathway, and mismatch repair pathway.</Detail>
      <Keyword>DNA repair</Keyword>
      <Ontology_ID>GO:0006281</Ontology_ID>
    </BioProcess>
    <BioProcess>
      <Detail>A system for the correction of errors in which an incorrect base, which cannot form hydrogen bonds with the corresponding base in the parent strand, is incorporated into the daughter strand. The mismatch repair system promotes genomic fidelity by repairing base-base mismatches, insertion-deletion loops and heterologies generated during DNA replication and recombination.</Detail>
      <Keyword>Mismatch repair</Keyword>
      <Ontology_ID>GO:0006298</Ontology_ID>
    </BioProcess>
    <BioProcess>
      <Detail>A change in state or activity of a cell (in terms of movement, secretion, enzyme production, gene expression, etc.) as a result of a stimulus indicating damage to its DNA from environmental insults or errors during metabolism.</Detail>
      <Keyword>Response to DNA damage stimulus</Keyword>
      <Ontology_ID>GO:0006974</Ontology_ID>
    </BioProcess>
  </BioProcess_List>
  <Molecule_Seq>
    <Protein_Seq>MSEAPRIQLLSPRLANQIAAGEVVERPASVAKELLENSLDAGSRRIDVEVEQGGIKLLRVRDDGRGIPADDLPLALARHATSKIRELEDLERVMSLGFRGEALASISSVARLTMTSRTADAGEAWQVETEGRDMQPRVQPAAHPVGTSVEVRDLFFNTPARRKFLRAEKTEFDHLQEVIKRLALARFDVAFHLRHNGKTIFALHEARDELARARRVGAVCGQAFLEQALPIEVERNGLHLWGWVGLPTFSRSQPDLQYFYVNGRMVRDKLVAHAVRQAYRDVLYNGRHPTFVLFFEVDPAVVDVNVHPTKHEVRFRDSRMVHDFLYGTLHRALGEVRPDDQLAPPGATSLTEPRPTGAAAGEFGPQGEMRLAESVLESPAARVGWSGGSSASGGSSGYSAYTRPEAPPSLAEAGGAYKAYFAPLPAGEAPAALPESAQDIPPLGYALAQLKGIYILAENAHGLVLVDMHAAHERITYERLKVAMASEGLRGQPLLVPESIAVSEREADCAEEHSSWFQRLGFELQRLGPESLAIRQIPALLKQAEATQLVRDVIADLLEYGTSDRIQAHLNELLGTMACHGAVRANRRLTLPEMNALLRDMEITERSGQCNHGRPTWTQLGLDELDKLFLRGR</Protein_Seq>
  </Molecule_Seq>
  <Gene>
    <Gene_Name>mutL</Gene_Name>
    <Gene_ID>878468</Gene_ID>
    <Genbank_ACCN>NC_002516</Genbank_ACCN>
    <Protein_ACCN>NP_253633</Protein_ACCN>
    <Gene_URL>http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/gene/878468</Gene_URL>
  </Gene>
  <PDB_List>
    <PDB>
      <PDB_Title>Model of DNA mismatch repair protein MutL</PDB_Title>
      <PDB_ID>ASD10900000_1</PDB_ID>
      <Resolution>-1.0</Resolution>
    </PDB>
  </PDB_List>
  <Create_Date>2013-11-12</Create_Date>
</Organism_Record>